<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alex P. Gates</title><link>http://alexpgates.com/</link><description>works on the internet</description><atom:link href="http://alexpgates.com/feeds/alex-p-gates.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fun &amp; practical applications for smart lighting</title><link>http://alexpgates.com/blog/2015/05/fun-and-practical-applications-for-smart-lighting</link><description>&lt;div class="row text-center span12"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/infotec2015.jpg" class="hero" alt="infotec2015" width="650"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk about smart lighting at &lt;a href="http://infotec.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Infotec&lt;/a&gt; in April where I discussed &lt;strong&gt;five reasons why you&amp;#8217;d want to consider smart lighting&lt;/strong&gt; in your home or office, &lt;strong&gt;various smart lighting technologies&lt;/strong&gt; available on the market, and &lt;strong&gt;some &lt;a href="/blog/tag/philips-hue.html"&gt;fun things I&amp;#8217;ve built&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; with Philips Hue&amp;nbsp;lighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a little &lt;strong&gt;recap of my talk&lt;/strong&gt;, a &lt;strong&gt;guide you can use to set up a Philips Hue bridge and lights for live conference demos&lt;/strong&gt;, and a &lt;strong&gt;video interview&lt;/strong&gt; with Jim Collison from &lt;a href="http://theaverageguy.tv/"&gt;theaverageguy.tv&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Five reasons why you&amp;#8217;d want to consider smart&amp;nbsp;lighting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KJQwkRjqAIY"&gt;his talk at Bright Day 3&lt;/a&gt; in Amsterdam last May, George Yianni, creator of the &lt;a href="http://www2.meethue.com/en-us/"&gt;Philips Hue lighting system&lt;/a&gt;, outlined the first four benefits to connected lighting and their motivation for developing the Hue lighting&amp;nbsp;system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reviewed these four benefits, and included one additional benefit I see to owning smart lighting&amp;nbsp;systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ambiance&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably the most obvious reason. Smart lighting allows you to control the color and temperature of your lights. This is a great way to add color to a room and set the proper mood for any&amp;nbsp;occasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine preparing for a dinner party in your kitchen. When cleaning and preparing food, you&amp;#8217;d want bright white lights to help you see. As the sun sets and your guests arrive, a warmer light would be more relaxing and definitely less harsh. Splashes of color also help create an inviting&amp;nbsp;atmosphere. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Biological&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little less obvious reason for choosing smart lighting relates to biology. Color temperature&amp;mdash;cool to warm&amp;mdash;has been proven to help people focus, relax, regain energy, and even recover from jet&amp;nbsp;lag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subtle differences in temperature and brightness can have dramatic effects on your productivity and&amp;nbsp;mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Soft&amp;nbsp;Security&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning to a dark house in the evening can be a little frightening. Smart lighting allows you to control the lights in your home or office through smartphone apps, geofencing rules, and timer systems. This ensures you&amp;#8217;ll never have to walk in to a dark house and fumble for your light switch ever&amp;nbsp;again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart lighting can also be integrated with other IoT technologies&amp;mdash;such as &lt;a href="https://nest.com/"&gt;Nest&lt;/a&gt; thermostats and smoke detectors&amp;mdash;to provide visual cues in an emergency situation. This allows you to illuminate your home in the event of an evacuation, or provide alerting mechanisms to people who may be hard of&amp;nbsp;hearing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Gentle&amp;nbsp;reminders&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hearing your phone chime for every single notification definitely gets old after a while. I&amp;#8217;m really interested in the idea of small environmental cues to alert you to helpful&amp;nbsp;information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, many people are using Hue lights in conjunction with &lt;a href="http://ifttt.com"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IFTTT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to remind them to bring an umbrella if the day&amp;#8217;s forecast calls for&amp;nbsp;rain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m using &lt;a href="https://github.com/bahamas10/hue-cli"&gt;a Hue command-line library&lt;/a&gt; with some longer-running scripts I use for work to alert me to a completed script or if errors were encountered along the&amp;nbsp;way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s easy to use smart lighting to remind you of calendar appointments, completed timers, or even when your favorite team scores during a&amp;nbsp;game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Pure geeky&amp;nbsp;fun&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; integrations with Philips Hue are very straightforward and fun to use. I&amp;#8217;ve built small apps that allow me to use &lt;a href="/blog/2013/04/voice-controlled-hue.html"&gt;weather data&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="/blog/2013/04/voice-controlled-hue.html"&gt;my voice&lt;/a&gt; to control my lights. I also built a totally silly and completely useless app that &lt;a href="/blog/2013/11/scanning-colors-to-hue.html"&gt;grabs dominant colors from a scanned document&lt;/a&gt; to change the colors of lights. &lt;a href="/blog/2014/08/strangers-please-control-my-kitchen-lights.html"&gt;You can also tweet&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/kitchencolors"&gt;@kitchencolors&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;#8217;d like to change the colors of the lights in my&amp;nbsp;kitchen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;My demo&amp;nbsp;setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some challenges to using Hue lights in live demos at conferences or other events. Since the Hue bridge needs to connect directly to a router, you&amp;#8217;ll want to be sure to bring your&amp;nbsp;router.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reset an old Airport Express and connected my Hue bridge before setting everythign up. Everything worked just fine when I plugged it in at the event&amp;nbsp;center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To control the lights, I used the &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/philips-hue/id557206189?mt=8"&gt;official Hue app&lt;/a&gt; on my iPad, which was connected to my Airport Express network. On my laptop I toggled back and forth between my conference WiFi and my private Airport Express network. This allowed me to control my lights using my local network, and also get online to pull up websites and videos using the conference&amp;nbsp;WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href="http://www.alfredapp.com/"&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt; workflows that executed &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BASH&lt;/span&gt; scripts to trigger more complex lighting sequences. &lt;a href="http://www.alfredapp.com/remote/"&gt;Alfred Remote&lt;/a&gt; made it easy to trigger these workflows right from my iPad, since my laptop was used for my slide&amp;nbsp;deck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Watch my follow-up interview with&amp;nbsp;Jim:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my talk, I had &lt;a href="/blog/2014/09/interview-cultivating-a-fun-and-creative-culture-with-a-distributed-team.html"&gt;another&lt;/a&gt; wonderful opportunity to chat with Jim Collison from &lt;a href="http://theaverageguy.tv/"&gt;theaverageguy.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="videoWrapper"&gt;
    &lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/N9nBiWXWcoc?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big thanks &lt;a href="http://aimforbrilliance.org/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AIM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for organizing &lt;a href="http://infotec.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Infotec&lt;/a&gt; and for giving me the opportunity to share some really fun things about smart lighting. Also, be sure to check out &lt;a href="http://theaverageguy.tv/"&gt;theaverageguy.tv&lt;/a&gt; for reviews, tech tips, and tons and tons of interesting&amp;nbsp;podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center top-padding download"&gt;
    &lt;a class="btn btn-large" href="http://webjam.org/blog-downloads/SmartLighting.pdf"&gt;Download my slides &lt;i class="fa fa-arrow-circle-down"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex P. Gates</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:alexpgates.com,2015-05-27:blog/2015/05/fun-and-practical-applications-for-smart-lighting</guid><category>Smart Lighting</category><category>Philips Hue</category><category>Speaking</category></item><item><title>Zapier post: How a Tiny (but Powerful) App Named Alfred Changed the Way I Work</title><link>http://alexpgates.com/blog/2014/10/zapier-post-alfred</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zapier.com/"&gt;Zapier&lt;/a&gt; is a really great way to automate workflows through webapp APIs (and even your own webhooks). They also have a &lt;a href="https://zapier.com/blog/"&gt;wonderful blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month I wrote a post about Alfred for their blog. It&amp;#8217;s basically a combination of the first two posts I wrote about Alfred (&lt;a href="http://alex.blog/blog/2014/07/working-smarter-with-alfred-custom-web-searches.html"&gt;Custom Web Searches&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="/blog/2014/07/working-smarter-with-alfred-workflows.html"&gt;Workflows&lt;/a&gt;) with a lot more about the other built-in&amp;nbsp;features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend installing Alfred and following&amp;nbsp;along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zapier.com/blog/alfred/"&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s the tutorial&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex P. Gates</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:alexpgates.com,2014-10-21:blog/2014/10/zapier-post-alfred</guid><category>Alfred</category></item><item><title>Interview: Cultivating a Fun &amp; Creative Culture with a Distributed Team</title><link>http://alexpgates.com/blog/2014/09/interview-cultivating-a-fun-and-creative-culture-with-a-distributed-team</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I sat down with &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jcollison"&gt;Jim Collison&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="http://theaverageguy.tv/"&gt;theaverageguy.tv&lt;/a&gt; after my talk at Heartland Developer&amp;nbsp;Conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="videoWrapper"&gt;
    &lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/VC2hNskgyH8?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the chat and the wonderful video,&amp;nbsp;Jim!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also want to thank &lt;a href="http://aimforbrilliance.org/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AIM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for organizing &lt;a href="http://www.heartlanddc.com/"&gt;Heartland Developer Conference&lt;/a&gt; and for giving me the opportunity to share the various tools and processes we use at &lt;a href="http://packdog.com"&gt;Pack&lt;/a&gt; to work as a distributed&amp;nbsp;team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks so&amp;nbsp;much!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/HDC.gif" class="margin" width="450" alt="Pack Faces at HDC"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="row text-center top-padding download"&gt;
    &lt;a class="btn btn-large" href="http://webjam.org/blog-downloads/HDC-AlexPGates.zip"&gt;Download my slides &lt;i class="fa fa-arrow-circle-down"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex P. Gates</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:alexpgates.com,2014-09-05:blog/2014/09/interview-cultivating-a-fun-and-creative-culture-with-a-distributed-team</guid><category>Productivity</category><category>Speaking</category></item><item><title>How to Walk with a Full Cup of Coffee</title><link>http://alexpgates.com/blog/2014/08/how-to-walk-with-a-full-cup-of-coffee</link><description>&lt;div class="row text-center span12"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/cup.jpg" class="hero" alt="a full cup of coffee"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At my first job out of college, I learned something from one of the customer service reps that I’ve used so incredibly&amp;nbsp;often. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was walking back from the break room with a very very full cup of coffee and struggling with it&amp;nbsp;spilling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She told me the secret to walking with a full cup of coffee: &lt;em&gt;don’t look at&amp;nbsp;it&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know how to hold a mug of coffee and you know how to walk. So just do that.  When you look at it, you try to correct yourself, and you end up causing the&amp;nbsp;spills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Trust&amp;nbsp;yourself&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that this tiny piece of advice extends beyond coffee spill prevention. It’s a reminder to be confident in things we innately know how to&amp;nbsp;do.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex P. Gates</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:alexpgates.com,2014-08-15:blog/2014/08/how-to-walk-with-a-full-cup-of-coffee</guid><category>Coffee</category><category>Life</category></item><item><title>Strangers, Please Control my Kitchen Lights</title><link>http://alexpgates.com/blog/2014/08/strangers-please-control-my-kitchen-lights</link><description>&lt;div class="row text-center span12"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/kitchencolors-header.jpg" class="hero" alt="kitchencolors" width="650"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;It occurred to me that I should probably let strangers from the internet control the lights in my&amp;nbsp;kitchen.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Because why&amp;nbsp;not?)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;And now you can, by tweeting to &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/kitchencolors"&gt;@kitchencolors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During our recent kitchen remodel, I made a special point to build in power outlets for a couple sets of &lt;a href="http://meethue.com/en-us/friends-of-hue/lightstrips/"&gt;Philips Hue LightStrips&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;a href="https://ifttt.com/hue"&gt;Philips Hue &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IFTTT&lt;/span&gt; channel&lt;/a&gt;, these lights have been set to turn on around sundown and turn off at&amp;nbsp;11pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s perfectly cool and all, but lately I&amp;#8217;ve been itching to &lt;em&gt;build&lt;/em&gt; something fun to take advantage of the bigger &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RGB&lt;/span&gt; color range available with the&amp;nbsp;LightStrips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally last night it dawned on me that I should let the internet choose the colors of my kitchen&amp;nbsp;lights. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Before I began, I wrote down these three&amp;nbsp;goals:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Make it fast! (No waiting on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IFTTT&lt;/span&gt; or anything like&amp;nbsp;that.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Step out of my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; comfort&amp;nbsp;zone.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Power this with my &lt;a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/"&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Make it&amp;nbsp;fast!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Philips Hue &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; works by making &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt; requests to a bridge connected to your local network. That, in itself, created some&amp;nbsp;limitations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thought was to schedule a cron job on a machine in my home network to run every minute and hit an endpoint on a public webserver to check for new color changes. That approach seemed pretty wasteful (and still pretty slow, honestly). That, and it&amp;#8217;d require building a front-end interface to interact with the&amp;nbsp;app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So then I thought about using Twitter to handle the color requests, and realized this would a perfect time to try the &lt;a href="https://dev.twitter.com/docs/streaming-apis/streams/user"&gt;user stream &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, since it seems to be nearly&amp;nbsp;instantaneous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step out of my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; comfort&amp;nbsp;zone&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I started thinking about how I&amp;#8217;d want people to make the color requests. Since &lt;a href="http://developers.meethue.com/"&gt;the Hue &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; accepts X &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Y coordinates from the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CIE_1931_color_space"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CIE&lt;/span&gt; color space&lt;/a&gt;, I knew we would need an easy way to translate casual color requests without being too limiting. In other words, I didn&amp;#8217;t want to simply hard-code 20 or so colors, because &lt;a href="http://www.newscenter.philips.com/main/standard/news/press/2013/20130807-philips-expands-the-smart-world-of-hue.wpd#.U-gnuNNdU1g"&gt;Hue actually supports &lt;em&gt;16 million&lt;/em&gt; colors&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://github.com/bahamas10/hue-cli"&gt;Hue command-line interface by bahamas10&lt;/a&gt; accepts &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt; color names and also hex color values. This tool runs on Node.js, and I was already familiar with it because I&amp;#8217;ve actually been using it for a few months to control my lights from the command-line. (&lt;a href="/images//prof.gif"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HOYVIN&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GLAVIN&lt;/span&gt;!&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t have much experience with Node.js, so this seemed like a perfect opportunity to try something&amp;nbsp;new.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next task was to figure out how to consume the Twitter user stream &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; from Node.js. After a little digging, I came across &lt;a href="https://github.com/outadoc/twitter-mentions-pushover"&gt;twitter-mentions-pushover&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="http://dev.outadoc.fr/"&gt;Baptist Candellier&lt;/a&gt;. This provided everything I needed to consume my user stream. I just trimmed off the part in the script that sends the tweet to Pushover, removed any @mentions and # symbols, and added the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPM&lt;/span&gt; module &lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.org/package/exec"&gt;exec()&lt;/a&gt; to send the color command to hue-cli. All said and done, I &lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt; wrote 6 lines of&amp;nbsp;code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Power this with my Raspberry&amp;nbsp;Pi&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the node process needs to be constantly running to consume the Twitter stream and pass requests to the Hue bridge, I wanted to keep my power usage low. The Raspberry Pi runs on a simple 5V power supply, and it&amp;#8217;s completely silent. It runs headless and sits nicely next to my modem, router, and hue&amp;nbsp;bridge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/rpi.jpg" class="margin" width="500"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing a fresh &lt;a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/downloads/"&gt;Raspbian Wheezy image&lt;/a&gt; was a breeze. Then I followed &lt;a href="https://learn.adafruit.com/raspberry-pi-hosting-node-red/setting-up-node-dot-js"&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; to set up&amp;nbsp;Node.js.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPM&lt;/span&gt;, I installed &lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.org/package/hue-cli"&gt;hue-cli&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.org/package/exec"&gt;exec&lt;/a&gt;. The other dependencies (&lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.org/package/entities"&gt;entities&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.org/package/ntwitter"&gt;ntwitter&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.org/package/request"&gt;request&lt;/a&gt;) shipped with &lt;a href="https://github.com/outadoc/twitter-mentions-pushover"&gt;twitter-mentions-pushover&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I created a fork of twitter-mentions-pushover and renamed the project &lt;a href="https://github.com/alexpgates/kitchencolors"&gt;Kitchencolors&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;See it in&amp;nbsp;action!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a hilariously dramatic video to show how quickly tweets are processed as&amp;nbsp;color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="videoWrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/103095002?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LOL&lt;/span&gt;. It was either that or the sound of my dishwasher&amp;nbsp;running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Give it a&amp;nbsp;try!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To change the colors of my kitchen lights, just send a tweet to &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/kitchencolors"&gt;@kitchencolors&lt;/a&gt; with a css color name &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; a hex&amp;nbsp;value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/tweet-to-kitchencolors.png" width="438"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I&amp;#8217;ve had people from all over the United States, England, Brazil, New Zealand, and Panama decide what color my kitchen should&amp;nbsp;be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Open up your Hue lights to&amp;nbsp;strangers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s still pretty rough around the edges, but you can &lt;a href="https://github.com/alexpgates/kitchencolors"&gt;download the source here&lt;/a&gt;! Future updates will include better color parsing to pull colors out of tweets that contain other text. If that sounds like fun, or if you have other feature ideas, please send me a pull&amp;nbsp;request!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex P. Gates</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:alexpgates.com,2014-08-10:blog/2014/08/strangers-please-control-my-kitchen-lights</guid><category>Philips Hue</category><category>Node.js</category><category>Raspberry Pi</category><category>Twitter</category></item><item><title>Working Smarter with Alfred: Workflows</title><link>http://alexpgates.com/blog/2014/07/working-smarter-with-alfred-workflows</link><description>&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/alfred-logo.png" alt="Alfred logo"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Hello again,&amp;nbsp;Alfred!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second post in a series on &lt;a href="http://alfredapp.com"&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt;, a productivity application for Mac &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an overview of Alfred, and to learn about using Custom Web Searches to work smarter and faster, &lt;a href="/blog/2014/07/working-smarter-with-alfred-custom-web-searches"&gt;read my first post in this series here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;#8217;m assuming you&amp;#8217;re already familiar with Alfred and have &lt;a href="https://buy.alfredapp.com/"&gt;purchased the Powerpack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Understanding&amp;nbsp;Workflows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Alfred Workflow is basically a chain of things that you want to do on your Mac incredibly&amp;nbsp;quickly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possibilities are honestly unlimited, so this makes it a bit complicated to actually explain what a Workflow &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; and how powerful they are. Instead, I&amp;#8217;ll just &lt;em&gt;show&lt;/em&gt; you a few of the Alfred Workflows I use to make my day-to-day tasks easier and more&amp;nbsp;efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are just a few examples that barely scratch the surface, but it should be enough to help you grasp the general idea of Alfred Workflows and get excited about downloading or creating your own Workflows to make your job&amp;nbsp;easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t reinvent the&amp;nbsp;wheel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many super smart Alfred users who have created many wonderful Workflows and shared them on the web. Websites like &lt;a href="http://www.alfredworkflow.com/"&gt;alfredworkflow.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.packal.org/"&gt;Packal&lt;/a&gt; have hundreds of available Workflows to download for free. You can also find lots of great resources on the &lt;a href="http://www.alfredforum.com/forum/3-share-your-workflows/"&gt;Alfred Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you search around, you&amp;#8217;ll likely find something that will shave off some time for things you frequently do on your Mac. I&amp;#8217;ve downloaded a few of these, and the following list contains Workflows I use quite&amp;nbsp;frequently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Super fast &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GIF&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Workflow!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pack&amp;#8217;s team is distributed, so we rely on &lt;a href="https://campfirenow.com/"&gt;Campfire&lt;/a&gt; as a central place for communication. Sometimes text just isn&amp;#8217;t the best avenue to convey emotion, so we (perhaps too frequently) harness the power of animated&amp;nbsp;gifs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://destroytoday.com/blog/gif-workflow/"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/alfred-dog-pug-wut.gif" class="margin" alt="pug wut"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/2227623/gifs/obama-kidding-me.gif"&gt;a proven fact&lt;/a&gt; that the hilarity of a gif reply diminishes over time, so it&amp;#8217;s absolutely essential to be quick with your response. &lt;a href="http://destroytoday.com/blog/gif-workflow/"&gt;Jonnie Hallman&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GIF&lt;/span&gt; Workflow&lt;/a&gt; can&amp;nbsp;help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Workflow allows you to harvest your own GIFs and store them in a public folder on Dropbox. Just add keywords in the filename when you save a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GIF&lt;/span&gt;, then search for them when you run the Workflow. &lt;a href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/2227623/gifs/kim-yes-clapping-good-joke.gif"&gt;Brilliant&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t forget about&amp;nbsp;emoji!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/carlosgaldino/alfred-emoji-workflow"&gt;Carlos Galdino&amp;#8217;s Alfred Emoji Workflow&lt;/a&gt; is the emoji equivalent of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GIF&lt;/span&gt; Workflow. Sometimes a reply just calls for something small, so Carlos has you&amp;nbsp;covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://github.com/carlosgaldino/alfred-emoji-workflow"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/alfred-emoji-workflow.png" alt="emoji workflow"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;iMessage to a&amp;nbsp;friend&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://eay.cc/projects/alfred-workflow-imessage-to-friend/"&gt;Stefan Grund&lt;/a&gt; made a really handy iMessage Workflow to quickly send an iMessage right from Alfred. It&amp;#8217;s not directly integrated to your Address Book, so you need to manually set up the Workflow for contacts that you message&amp;nbsp;frequently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://eay.cc/projects/alfred-workflow-imessage-to-friend/"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/alfred-imessage.png" alt="imessage workflow"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like some other plugins, a little setup in the beginning saves lots of time down the&amp;nbsp;road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Phillips Hue&amp;nbsp;Controller&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/benknight"&gt;Benjamin Knight&lt;/a&gt; wrote a Workflow to control &lt;a href="http://meethue.com/"&gt;Phillips Hue lights&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;ve written &lt;a href="/blog/tag/philips-hue.html"&gt; a couple posts&lt;/a&gt; about Philips Hue bulbs, and anyone who knows me knows I get really excited about these&amp;nbsp;things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://github.com/benknight"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/alfred-hue-overview.png" alt="hue workflow"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Ben&amp;#8217;s Workflow, I&amp;#8217;m able to control the lights in my house right inside&amp;nbsp;Alfred. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Custom Alfred&amp;nbsp;Workflows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, most of the Workflows that I&amp;#8217;ve downloaded really don&amp;#8217;t do too much to make my &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt; more efficient. But that doesn&amp;#8217;t mean &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; Workflows are just for fun and&amp;nbsp;games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few Workflows I&amp;#8217;ve put together to help around the&amp;nbsp;office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Email the Pack&amp;nbsp;Team&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/alfred-workflow-setup.png" alt="Alfred Workflow Setup"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are five us on the Pack team, so every time I wanted to send an email to everyone on the team, I&amp;#8217;d &lt;em&gt;cmd+tab&lt;/em&gt; to my mail program (Sparrow), &lt;em&gt;cmd+n&lt;/em&gt; to open a new email. Then I&amp;#8217;d start typing each team member&amp;#8217;s name, followed by tab, until all four were in the &lt;em&gt;To&lt;/em&gt; field. &lt;em&gt;At best&lt;/em&gt;, that&amp;#8217;s 14&amp;nbsp;keystrokes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Alfred, I&amp;#8217;ve reduced it to&amp;nbsp;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just invoke quicksilver, and begin typing &lt;em&gt;emailpack&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/alfred-email-pack.png" alt="Alfred Email Pack"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Alfred detects what I&amp;#8217;m typing, (it usually just takes the &lt;em&gt;e&lt;/em&gt;) I just hit&amp;nbsp;enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immediately, a new message window is opened with everyone&amp;#8217;s email address in the &lt;em&gt;To&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/alfred-email-pack-sparrow.png" alt="Alfred Email Pack"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can invoke this Workflow from &lt;em&gt;anywhere&lt;/em&gt; on my Mac. In other words, I don&amp;#8217;t need to be in Sparrow (or even have Sparrow open, for that&amp;nbsp;matter).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Workflow is a bit more complicated to set up, since it requires a little Applescript to make it&amp;nbsp;happen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Begin by creating a new blank Workflow, then set your keyword input. For your action, choose &lt;em&gt;Run Script&lt;/em&gt;. Choose &lt;code&gt;/usr/bin/osascript&lt;/code&gt; from the Language dropdown. Then, use this as a guide for creating your own email&amp;nbsp;list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;tell&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;application&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Sparrow&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nb"&gt;activate&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;set&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;theMessage&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;make&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;outgoing&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;message&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;properties&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;subject&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;tell&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;theMessage&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="nb"&gt;make&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;recipient&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;at&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;recipients&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;properties&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Fred&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;address&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;fred@flintstone.com&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="nb"&gt;make&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;recipient&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;at&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;recipients&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;properties&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Wilma&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;address&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;wilma@flintstone.com&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="nb"&gt;make&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;recipient&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;at&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;recipients&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;properties&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Barney&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;address&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;barney@rubble.com&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="nb"&gt;make&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;recipient&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;at&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;recipients&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;properties&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Betty&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;address&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;betty@rubble.com&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
         &lt;span class="nv"&gt;compose&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;tell&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;tell&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Yes, it takes a bit of time to get this set up initially, but all those saved keystrokes add up over time. Remember, this example is for Sparrow only, but it&amp;#8217;d be easy to do something very similar for&amp;nbsp;Mail.app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Add an item to my Pep Rally&amp;nbsp;inbox&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Pack, we use a task collaboration app we built at &lt;a href="http://whatcheer.com"&gt;What Cheer&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;a href="http://peprallyapp.com"&gt;Pep Rally&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately Pep Rally isn&amp;#8217;t available to the public, but it&amp;#8217;s a tool that we rely on&amp;nbsp;heavily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One feature of Pep Rally I frequently use is the inbox. Adding an item to my inbox is a quick way to document a task quickly when I&amp;#8217;m in the middle of completing another&amp;nbsp;task. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://velvetcache.org"&gt;Hobbs&lt;/a&gt; added a Python command line tool to interact with Pep Rally, so for this Workflow action I execute a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BASH&lt;/span&gt; script to use it by selecting &lt;code&gt;/bin/bash&lt;/code&gt; from the Language&amp;nbsp;dropdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;created&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;/Applications/MAMP/htdocs/Pep-Rally/peprally_python/scripts/peprally inbox:create &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;{query}&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;[[&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$created&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; *TRUE* &lt;span class="o"&gt;]]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;{query}&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;fi&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Instead of opening Pep Rally and clicking on my inbox tab, I simply invoke Alfred, begin typing &lt;em&gt;inbox&lt;/em&gt;, then hit tab and start typing what I need to&amp;nbsp;remember. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/alfred-peprally-inbox.png" alt="Alfred Pep Rally Inbox"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this Workflow, I added a Post Notification output so Growl alerts me that my task was successfully added. To do this, I clicked the &lt;em&gt;+&lt;/em&gt; symbol, then clicked &lt;em&gt;Outputs&lt;/em&gt; &amp;#10142; &lt;em&gt;Post Notification&lt;/em&gt;. With Alfred, you can output to Growl or Notification Center, and set a custom title and text for the notification. Using &lt;code&gt;{query}&lt;/code&gt; in either of these fields will use the output from the previous&amp;nbsp;action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/alfred-growl-peprally.png" alt="Alfred Growl"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is a little vague, I know. But I chose to include it so you can see an example of extending Alfred to a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; and to your own&amp;nbsp;tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Go!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in &lt;a href="/blog/2014/07/working-smarter-with-alfred-custom-web-searches"&gt;my first post about Alfred Custom Web Searches&lt;/a&gt;, you should add helpful Workflows slowly. If you add too many new tools at once, you&amp;#8217;ll never keep track of them all and all the potential efficiencies will be&amp;nbsp;lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon these new tools will become second nature, and all the seconds you save in your day-to-day will definitely add&amp;nbsp;up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you have an Alfred Workflow you&amp;#8217;d like me to check out? &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;&amp;#97;&amp;#108;&amp;#101;&amp;#120;&amp;#64;&amp;#119;&amp;#104;&amp;#97;&amp;#116;&amp;#99;&amp;#104;&amp;#101;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;"&gt;Let me know&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex P. Gates</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:alexpgates.com,2014-07-27:blog/2014/07/working-smarter-with-alfred-workflows</guid><category>Alfred</category><category>Productivity</category><category>Mac</category></item><item><title>Felix: a PHP / Twilio Group Messaging Tool</title><link>http://alexpgates.com/blog/2014/07/group-texting-with-php-and-twilio</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Keep the whole group in the&amp;nbsp;loop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my first year as an Industry Advisor at &lt;a href="http://www.businesshorizonsiowa.org/"&gt;Business Horizons&lt;/a&gt; (a week-long summer program for Iowa high school students) it occurred to me that we really didn&amp;#8217;t have a way for everyone to quickly get messages to the group in the event of a schedule change or&amp;nbsp;emergency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were about 20 or so advisors. Some had iPhones, some had Androids, and some had&amp;nbsp;flip-phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In just a couple hours, I put together a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt; tool using &lt;a href="http://twilio.com"&gt;Twilio&lt;/a&gt; that we&amp;#8217;ve used for the last two&amp;nbsp;years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I updated the tool to use &lt;a href="https://github.com/twilio/twilio-php"&gt;Twilio&amp;#8217;s updated &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; library&lt;/a&gt;, put &lt;a href="https://github.com/alexpgates/felix"&gt;everything on Github&lt;/a&gt;, and named it after my 6-week old baby&amp;nbsp;boy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;No smartphone&amp;nbsp;required&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Felix could be very useful for event organizers, summer camp counselors, schools, or anyone looking for an easy and inexpensive way to keep a group connected without requiring anyone to download an app or own a&amp;nbsp;smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The onboarding flow allows users to join the group by texting anything to the number, then following simple&amp;nbsp;directions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Members can leave the group by sending: &lt;code&gt;-stop&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Members can change their nicknames by sending: &lt;code&gt;-name&lt;/code&gt;, followed by their new&amp;nbsp;nickname.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The group administrator receives an alert when new members&amp;nbsp;join.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All messages are logged in the&amp;nbsp;database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Messages can contain up to 1600&amp;nbsp;characters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Join&amp;nbsp;Flow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members join the group by texting anything to the phone number. After replying with your name, you&amp;#8217;re all&amp;nbsp;set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/felix-join-flow.png" class="margin" width="300px"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Use&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, Felix is also handy for some good old&amp;nbsp;trash-talking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/felix-use.png" class="margin" width="300px"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Requirements &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Felix requires a Twilio account, a verified phone number, MySQL, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;, and a web host. Everything you need to know can be found on &lt;a href="https://github.com/alexpgates/felix"&gt;the Github page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Give it a&amp;nbsp;try!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to shoot me an email if you have any questions or run in to any issues. If you fix any bugs or add any features, send me a pull request on&amp;nbsp;Github!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this came in handy for your event, I&amp;#8217;d love to hear about&amp;nbsp;it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center top-padding download"&gt;
    &lt;a class="btn btn-large" href="https://github.com/alexpgates/felix/archive/master.zip"&gt;Download Felix &lt;i class="fa fa-arrow-circle-down"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex P. Gates</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:alexpgates.com,2014-07-14:blog/2014/07/group-texting-with-php-and-twilio</guid><category>Twilio</category><category>PHP</category><category>SMS</category></item><item><title>Working Smarter with Alfred: Custom Web Searches</title><link>http://alexpgates.com/blog/2014/07/working-smarter-with-alfred-custom-web-searches</link><description>&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/alfred-logo.png" alt="Alfred logo"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Meet&amp;nbsp;Alfred!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://alfredapp.com"&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt; is a productivity application for Mac &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the box, it&amp;#8217;s a tremendously useful tool that helps you quickly launch apps with a few keystrokes or self-assigned hotkeys. 
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/alfred-launch-chrome.png" alt="Launching apps with Alfred"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
You can use Alfred to search all sorts of&amp;nbsp;websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/alfred-search-youtube.png" alt="Search YouTube with Alfred"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can even do lots of little things right inside Alfred, like perform quick&amp;nbsp;calculations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/alfred-calculator.png" alt="Alfred calculator"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Step one: buy the&amp;nbsp;Powerpack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create custom web searches (and get the most out of Alfred), you need to &lt;a href="http://www.alfredapp.com/powerpack/"&gt;buy the Powerpack&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to creating custom web searches, the Powerpack gives you the ability to create create and import workflows, access clipboard history, manage a snippet library, and import beautiful custom&amp;nbsp;themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ll get to all those other things in later articles in this series. For now, I&amp;#8217;ll show you how to use custom web searches to make opening and searching &lt;em&gt;any site&lt;/em&gt;, including your own custom admin tools, much more&amp;nbsp;efficient. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Use a custom web search to quickly launch any&amp;nbsp;website&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While working on &lt;a href="http://packdog.com"&gt;Pack&lt;/a&gt;, I frequently open our admin site. Instead of &lt;em&gt;cmd+tabing&lt;/em&gt; to Chrome and clicking a bookmark or typing the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;, I simply invoke Alfred (&lt;em&gt;option+space&lt;/em&gt;) and begin typing &lt;em&gt;packadmin&lt;/em&gt;. As soon as Alfred recognizes what I&amp;#8217;m typing, I hit enter and Chrome brings up the admin site. Like&amp;nbsp;magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/alfred-pack-admin.png" alt="Alfred Pack Admin"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Set it&amp;nbsp;up&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To set this up for any website, click on &lt;em&gt;Web Search&lt;/em&gt; under the &lt;em&gt;Features&lt;/em&gt; tab in Alfred Preferences. Then click &lt;em&gt;Add Custom Search&lt;/em&gt; at the bottom&amp;nbsp;right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Search &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; text box, then assign a title (this will appear in Alfred when you start typing). Then set a keyword (this is what you start typing after invoking Alfred to open the website.) Finally, add a nice icon to keep everything looking&amp;nbsp;fancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/alfred-custom-search-launch-site.png" class="margin" alt="Set up Alfred to quickly launch any website"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you click &lt;em&gt;save&lt;/em&gt;, test it out by invoking Alfred and typing your keyword. Now you&amp;#8217;ll be able to quickly launch this website no matter where you are on your Mac, even if your browser is&amp;nbsp;closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Search in a&amp;nbsp;jiffy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pack admin site gives us a search tool to find dogs by name and users by name or email address. This is something I do multiple times per&amp;nbsp;day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of opening the admin site and performing a search from a search field, Alfred allows me to skip the middleman and go directly to the search&amp;nbsp;results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To search for a dog, I simply invoke Alfred and type &lt;em&gt;dog&lt;/em&gt; followed by a tab, and the name of the dog I&amp;#8217;m looking&amp;nbsp;for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/alfred-pack-dogs.png" alt="Alfred Pack Dog Search"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To search for a user, I start typing &lt;em&gt;human&lt;/em&gt; then tab, then the name or email address of the Pack user I want to find. After hitting enter, I&amp;#8217;m taken directly to the search&amp;nbsp;results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/alfred-pack-humans.png" alt="Alfred Pack Human Search"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Set it&amp;nbsp;up&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up a custom web search is easy. In order for this to work, though, you need the name of the query parameter used in your search results. In my case, it&amp;#8217;s &lt;code&gt;search&lt;/code&gt;. YouTube, for example, uses &lt;code&gt;search_query&lt;/code&gt;. The easiest way to find this is to perform a search using the regular search field, then look at everything that comes after the &lt;code&gt;?&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; on your results page. You&amp;#8217;ll find&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the first example, add this in the &lt;em&gt;Web Search&lt;/em&gt; pane under the &lt;em&gt;Features&lt;/em&gt; tab in Alfred Preferences. Click Add Custom Search on the bottom right of the screen. Then add the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; for your results page in the &lt;em&gt;Search &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; field. Use &lt;code&gt;{query}&lt;/code&gt; as the variable that is passed from the Alfred window. Finally, set your title, keyword, and&amp;nbsp;icon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/alfred-custom-search-setup.png" class="margin" alt="Alfred Pack Admin"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s it! Adding custom web searches is a great way to save keystrokes, mouse clicks, and page loads. Plus, when your co-workers notice what you&amp;#8217;ve done, they&amp;#8217;ll think you&amp;#8217;re super&amp;nbsp;smart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Go!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alfred can do &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of things to help speed up your workflow. The trick is to take things slowly and add these improvements to your workflow over time. If you try to cram too many things in at once, you&amp;#8217;ll never remember them all, and you&amp;#8217;ll easily fall back into old, wasteful&amp;nbsp;habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Custom web searches are a perfect first step to learning Alfred. Master this, then you&amp;#8217;ll be ready for the next article in the &lt;em&gt;Working Smarter with Alfred&lt;/em&gt; series: &lt;a href="/blog/2014/07/working-smarter-with-alfred-workflows"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Workflows.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex P. Gates</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:alexpgates.com,2014-07-03:blog/2014/07/working-smarter-with-alfred-custom-web-searches</guid><category>Alfred</category><category>Productivity</category><category>Mac</category></item><item><title>Video: Pack Presents at 1 Million Cups</title><link>http://alexpgates.com/blog/2014/04/pack-presents-at-1-million-cups</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://packdog.com"&gt;Pack&lt;/a&gt; was invited to present at &lt;a href="http://www.1millioncups.com/"&gt;1 Million Cups&lt;/a&gt; in Omaha on April 2, 2014. Here&amp;#8217;s a video of our&amp;nbsp;presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pack, in six&amp;nbsp;minutes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="videoWrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/90800707?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Thank&amp;nbsp;you!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href="http://www.nebraskaentrepreneurship.com/"&gt;Nebraska Entrepreneurship&lt;/a&gt; for recording and publishing the video. And big thanks to the &lt;a href="http://omaha.sites.1millioncups.com/"&gt;Omaha 1 Million Cups&lt;/a&gt; organizers for inviting&amp;nbsp;us!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex P. Gates</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:alexpgates.com,2014-04-05:blog/2014/04/pack-presents-at-1-million-cups</guid><category>Pack</category><category>Speaking</category></item><item><title>Scanning Colors to Philips Hue</title><link>http://alexpgates.com/blog/2013/11/scanning-colors-to-hue</link><description>&lt;div class="videoWrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/100126411?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What is&amp;nbsp;this?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/alexpgates/color-scan"&gt;color-scan&lt;/a&gt; grabs the dominant color(s) from images and passes the color(s) to &lt;a href="https://www.meethue.com/en-US"&gt;Philips Hue lights&lt;/a&gt;. You can decide if you want to send the main color to a group of lights, or individual colors to individual lights. It also works with scanned photos, of course, or with any jpeg that you drop in the directory. You don&amp;#8217;t actually &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; the&amp;nbsp;scanner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can can decide whether you want the main dominant color on all your lights &lt;code&gt;$color_mode = 'single';&lt;/code&gt;, or if you&amp;#8217;d like to grab a palette of colors to send to individual bulbs &lt;code&gt;$color_mode = 'multi';&lt;/code&gt;. The example in the video demonstrates using the &amp;#8220;single&amp;#8221; color&amp;nbsp;mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How does it&amp;nbsp;work?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the process script is called, it grabs the latest image from a directory. Color Thief handles the color quantization and provides &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RGB&lt;/span&gt; colors. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RGB&lt;/span&gt; is converted to the the xy color space, then sent to your Hue&amp;nbsp;bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Where can I get&amp;nbsp;this?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href="https://github.com/alexpgates/color-scan"&gt;fork it&lt;/a&gt; from&amp;nbsp;GitHub!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How do the settings&amp;nbsp;work?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;?php&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$color_mode&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;multi&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="c1"&gt;// &amp;quot;multi&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;single&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;// &amp;quot;multi&amp;quot; uses different colors for each light (defined in $light_ids), &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;// &amp;quot;single&amp;quot; uses the most dominant color found in the image for a Hue group (defined in $group_id)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$light_ids&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;// ids of your Hue lights that you want to use with color-scan&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;// Grab these from your bridge. http://developers.meethue.com/1_lightsapi.html&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$brightness&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;150&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;// 0 - 255 http://developers.meethue.com/1_lightsapi.html&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$group_id&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;// must be set  if using single color mode;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;// Grab this from your bridge. http://developers.meethue.com/2_groupsapi.html&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$path&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;/path/to/your/images/&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;// directory where you want to look for an image to process&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$bridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;x.x.x.x&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;// ip address of your internal bridge&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$hue_key&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;hue-user&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;// valid api user&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c1"&gt;//$debug = &amp;#39;debug&amp;#39;; // uncomment this for some debug info&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;?&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;*Note: color-scan doesn&amp;#8217;t handle registering a user on your bridge. You&amp;#8217;ll need to handle that &lt;a href="http://developers.meethue.com/4_configurationapi.html"&gt;on your own&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How do I use&amp;nbsp;this?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After adjusting the settings to fit your Hue setup, drop a jpeg in the directory you defined in &lt;code&gt;$path&lt;/code&gt;. Then run&amp;nbsp;process.php.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why did you make this (totally useless)&amp;nbsp;thing?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For fun, of course! I wanted to build something that would allow me to scan an image (or a piece of paper with some color) and have my lights change to match the dominant color(s) in the scanned image with the press of a&amp;nbsp;button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pulled that all together with color-scan + the addition of a folder action in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; X that runs process.php when a new file is added to the directory I defined in $path. I have a profile in the Fujitsu settings that dumps new images in this directory, so it&amp;#8217;s all triggered by pressing the button on my&amp;nbsp;scanner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="'OS X Folder Action setup'" src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/2227623/blog-images/XNMDVF-Screen_Shot_2013-11-22_at_3.03.28_PM.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Can&amp;#8217;t you already do this with digital images and the Hue&amp;nbsp;app?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes. But I just got this fancy new scanner and I wanted to hook it up to my light&amp;nbsp;bulbs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dependencies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This uses a &lt;a href="https://github.com/ksubileau/color-thief-php"&gt;color-thief-php&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="http://kevinsubileau.fr"&gt;Kevin Subileau&lt;/a&gt;, which is a port of &lt;a href="https://github.com/lokesh/color-thief," title="Color Thief"&gt;Color Thief&lt;/a&gt; written by &lt;a href="http://lokeshdhakar.com/"&gt;Lokesh&amp;nbsp;Dhakar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; (Only tested in 5.3.6) with&amp;nbsp;cURL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;License&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;color-scan is &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;licensed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Color Thief has it&amp;#8217;s own license, so check &lt;a href="https://github.com/lokesh/color-thief"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/ksubileau/color-thief-php"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Want more&amp;nbsp;Hue?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s an &lt;a href="/blog/2013/04/voice-controlled-hue.html"&gt;earlier post&lt;/a&gt; about using voice commands and weather data to control these&amp;nbsp;lights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center top-padding download"&gt;
    &lt;a class="btn btn-large" href="https://github.com/alexpgates/color-scan"&gt;Download color-scan &lt;i class="fa fa-arrow-circle-down"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex P. Gates</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>tag:alexpgates.com,2013-11-17:blog/2013/11/scanning-colors-to-hue</guid><category>Philips Hue</category><category>PHP</category><category>Color Quantization</category></item><item><title>“Hello world! … Hello world!” with annyang.js &amp; speak.js</title><link>http://alexpgates.com/blog/2013/09/annyang-js-and-speak-js</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://velvetcache.org"&gt;Hobbs&lt;/a&gt; sent me a link to &lt;a href="https://www.talater.com/annyang/"&gt;annyang.js&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://github.com/TalAter"&gt;Tal Ater&lt;/a&gt; because he thought it&amp;#8217;d be right up my alley. (He&amp;#8217;s right! It is! And it&amp;#8217;s not just for the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/talater/status/380059244017356800"&gt;Arrested Development reference&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;annyang.js&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.talater.com/annyang/"&gt;Annyang&lt;/a&gt; is &amp;#8220;a tiny javascript library that lets your users control your site with voice commands.&amp;#8221; It can do a lot for weighing in less than 1k. Annyang uses browser-based WebSpeech APIs and your computers microphone to translate speech-to-text and respond according to your commands. Annyang handles some pretty complex commands using variables, wildcards, optional ignoring, etc. There&amp;#8217;s a lot of great possibilities with annyang, and when I have some extra time I plan on using it to control a set of &lt;a href="https://www.meethue.com"&gt;Hue lights&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t have a lot of extra play time at the moment, but I wanted to quickly throw something together to try&amp;nbsp;annyang. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;speak.js&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/kripken/speak.js/"&gt;Speak.js&lt;/a&gt;, by &lt;a href="https://github.com/kripken"&gt;Alon Zakai&lt;/a&gt; is a javascript port of the eSpeak speech synthesizer. Speak.js enables text-to-speech in the browser using JavaScript and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML5&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Putting them&amp;nbsp;together&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combining annyang.js and speak.js seemed like fun, so I created &lt;a href="http://webjam.org/speak/" target="_blank"&gt;a little demo&lt;/a&gt;. Annyang.js listens to what you say, and speak.js repeats it back to&amp;nbsp;you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;script&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;src=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;speakClient.js&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;script&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;src=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;annyang.min.js&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;id=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;audio&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;script&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;type=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    if (annyang) {

      var sayThis = function(repeat) {
        speak(repeat);
      }

      // Let&amp;#39;s define a command.
      var commands = {
        &amp;#39;*repeat&amp;#39;: sayThis
      };

      // Turn on debugging for the console
      annyang.debug();

      // Initialize annyang with our commands
      annyang.init(commands);

      // Start listening.
      annyang.start();
    }
  &lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In the above example, we begin by checking to see if annyang will work in this browser. If so, we define a function called &lt;code&gt;sayThis&lt;/code&gt; that takes the output from our wildcard variable in annyong called &lt;code&gt;*repeat&lt;/code&gt; and uses the speak.js function &lt;code&gt;speak()&lt;/code&gt; to output a .wav file to &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div id="audio"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://webjam.org/speak/" target="_blank"&gt;Try the demo&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex P. Gates</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:alexpgates.com,2013-09-19:blog/2013/09/annyang-js-and-speak-js</guid><category>JavaScript</category></item><item><title>What’s Under the Hood?</title><link>http://alexpgates.com/blog/2013/06/whats-under-the-hood</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Many months ago, &lt;a href="http://christopherkollars.com"&gt;a buddy&lt;/a&gt; sent me &lt;a href="http://kylerush.net/blog/meet-the-obama-campaigns-250-million-fundraising-platform/"&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; written by &lt;a href="http://kylerush.net/"&gt;Kyle Rush&lt;/a&gt; about the technology stack behind the Obama campaign&amp;#8217;s fundraising platform. Kyle mentioned &lt;a href="http://jekyllrb.com/"&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, a static site generator written in Ruby, and recommended giving it a whirl to create fast, simple websites without the need for a bloated &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CMS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not a Ruby guy, and despite making an attempt to get things working properly on my Mac, I backed out of the rabbit hole and instead decided to give &lt;a href="http://docs.getpelican.com/en/latest/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; a try. It&amp;#8217;s written in Python, and uses the &lt;a href="http://jinja.pocoo.org/docs/"&gt;Jinja2&lt;/a&gt; templating&amp;nbsp;language.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get up and running, I followed &lt;a href="http://martinbrochhaus.com/pelican.html"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; handy (but now outdated) guide by &lt;a href="http://martinbrochhaus.com"&gt;Martin Brochhaus&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;small&gt;(Note: Here&amp;#8217;s Martin&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://martinbrochhaus.com/pelican2.html"&gt;updated guide&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting everything configured and deployed to &lt;a href="http://pages.github.com/"&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;, I started working on an &lt;em&gt;ugly&lt;/em&gt; theme based off the default Pelican template. I never finished it. Then, &lt;a href="http://whatcheer.com"&gt;What Cheer&lt;/a&gt; announced our &lt;a href="http://whatcheer.com/pack/"&gt;transition&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="http://packlove.com"&gt;Pack&lt;/a&gt;, and things got pretty busy for a&amp;nbsp;while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fast-forward six&amp;nbsp;months&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked things up again a couple weeks ago after reading about the &lt;a href="http://blog.getpelican.com/pelican-3.2-released.html"&gt;updates&lt;/a&gt; to Pelican. I began piecing together this current theme using &lt;a href="http://twitter.github.io/bootstrap/"&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;. (I haven&amp;#8217;t worked with any other front-end frameworks, but I&amp;#8217;ve been using it on &lt;a href="http://news.packlove.com/admin/"&gt;some stuff&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;#8217;m building with Pack, and also a &lt;a href="http://yearbooks.edison-pta.org"&gt;Yearbook project&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PTA&lt;/span&gt;.) I like it. Since the bulk of my front-end development happened between 1996 and 2004, it&amp;#8217;s allowed me get back in the game pretty&amp;nbsp;quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A complete list of&amp;nbsp;tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://docs.getpelican.com/en/latest/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; - A static site generator written in&amp;nbsp;Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://jinja.pocoo.org/docs/"&gt;Jinja2&lt;/a&gt; - A templating language for Python used to create Pelican&amp;nbsp;themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/"&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; - A lightweight markup language to quickly write&amp;nbsp;content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.github.io/bootstrap/"&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; - A  front-end framework - helpful for responsive&amp;nbsp;development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/fonts/"&gt;Google Fonts&lt;/a&gt; - For nicer&amp;nbsp;fonts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://pygments.org/"&gt;Pygments&lt;/a&gt; - For syntax&amp;nbsp;highlighting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-typogrify"&gt;Typogrify&lt;/a&gt; - To fancy up the text a&amp;nbsp;bit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://docs.fabfile.org/en/1.6/"&gt;Fabric&lt;/a&gt; - To streamline&amp;nbsp;deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://pages.github.com/"&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; - Fast, reliable&amp;nbsp;hosting &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The&amp;nbsp;process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Install&amp;nbsp;Pelican&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, here&amp;#8217;s Martin Brochhaus&amp;#8217; &lt;a href="http://martinbrochhaus.com/pelican2.html"&gt;updated guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Create your first&amp;nbsp;post&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Include your metadata at the top. &lt;small&gt;(More &lt;a href="http://docs.getpelican.com/en/latest/getting_started.html#writing-content-using-pelican"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Title: What&amp;#39;s Under the Hood?
Date: 2013-06-22
Summary: From Markdown to static HTML, by way of Pelican, Jinja2, Bootstrap, and more.
Slug: whats-under-the-hood
Tags: Pelican, Boostrap, Github

Many months ago, [a buddy](http://christopherkollars.com) sent me ...
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Preview!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use two separate config files for Pelican. One uses relative URLs (so I can preview locally), and the other generates absolute URLs for production. To avoid typing the full Pelican commands to generate the output, I use this&amp;nbsp;fabfile.py:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;Fabric tasks for generating HTML&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
from __future__ import with_statement

from fabric.api import lcd, &lt;span class="nb"&gt;local&lt;/span&gt;, settings

def pub&lt;span class="o"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;:
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;Re-generates the output using absolute urls.&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nb"&gt;local&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;pelican . -o ../ -s settings.py&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

def dev&lt;span class="o"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;:
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;Re-generates the output using relative urls.&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nb"&gt;local&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;pelican . -o ../ -s local_settings.py&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Preview&amp;nbsp;locally&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;fab dev
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Then I check it out on my local&amp;nbsp;vhost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Deploy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If everything looks okay, I generate the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; with absolute&amp;nbsp;URLs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;fab pub
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Then simply commit my changes to&amp;nbsp;Github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;So far, so&amp;nbsp;good&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m the kind of guy who will spend 15 hours hacking my Wii to play 15 minutes of old &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NES&lt;/span&gt; games. I&amp;#8217;m optimistic that an easy, fast, and fun way to manage a new blog will encourage me to get my act together and finally start writing somewhat&amp;nbsp;regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Get the&amp;nbsp;theme&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fork the current version of this theme on &lt;a href="https://github.com/alexpgates/alexpgates.github.com/tree/master/themes/apg"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. It really wasn&amp;#8217;t built with with sharing in mind, but you&amp;#8217;re free to use what you&amp;nbsp;can!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row text-center top-padding download"&gt;
    &lt;a class="btn btn-large" href="https://github.com/alexpgates/alexpgates.github.com/tree/master/themes/apg"&gt;Download this theme &lt;i class="fa fa-arrow-circle-down"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex P. Gates</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:alexpgates.com,2013-06-22:blog/2013/06/whats-under-the-hood</guid><category>Pelican</category><category>Bootstrap</category><category>Github</category></item><item><title>Voice &amp; Weather Controlled Philips Hue Lights</title><link>http://alexpgates.com/blog/2013/04/voice-controlled-hue</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Voice&amp;nbsp;control&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very simple demonstration of using voice commands to control Philips Hue light bulbs. In this example, I&amp;#8217;m using Chrome&amp;#8217;s x-webkit-speech speech input and &lt;a href="https://github.com/danray0424/phpHue"&gt;Dan Ray&amp;#8217;s phpHue&lt;/a&gt; to interact with the Hue&amp;nbsp;system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="videoWrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/rOW7RapR_d8?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Controlling lights using weather&amp;nbsp;data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a lightning talk I gave at &lt;a href="http://nebraskajs.com"&gt;NebraskaJS&lt;/a&gt; about Hue and this voice controlled application, and how I&amp;#8217;m also using weather data to control these&amp;nbsp;lights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="videoWrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/wsFSLDluypk?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Thanks &lt;a href="http://techomaha.com/"&gt;TechOmaha&lt;/a&gt; for the video!&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Alex P. Gates</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:alexpgates.com,2013-04-27:blog/2013/04/voice-controlled-hue</guid><category>Philips Hue</category><category>Speaking</category></item></channel></rss>